Finding Aid for the United Republicans of California records LSC.1737
UCLA Library Special Collections
United Republicans of California records
1962-1973
UCLA Library Special Collections
United Republicans of California
LSC.1737
0.8 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
The United Republicans of California (UROC) was founded in 1963 by California State Assemblymen Bruce Reagan and Joe Shell and was developed to promote the principles of freedom and the Constitution in the United States. Their influence has aided conservative politicians such as Barry Goldwater, John Ashbrook, and Ronald Reagan. These records span from 1962 to 1973 and contain materials produced by the United Republicans of California, including political pamphlets, brochures, meeting minutes, correspondence and newspaper and other press clippings.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Jane A. Crosby, 2006.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9982728243606533
Biography/History
The United Republicans of California (UROC) was a grassroots Republican volunteer organization founded in 1963 by Assemblymen Bruce Reagan and Joe Shell. An organization composed of volunteers, UROC was developed as both an alternative to establishment Republican organizations within California and as a platform to elect Republican politicians who shared UROC's conservative Constitutional views. Their goals included promoting the principles of freedom and the Constitution, recruiting and registering Republican voters in California, and aiding in the election of Republican candidates who adhere to those principles. UROC did not gain much traction historically.
Scope and Content
The records span from 1962 to 1973 and contain political pamphlets, brochures, correspondence, and press and newspaper clippings. Also included are founding and educational documents; publications including UROC's Round-Up; editorials; reports focused on American patriotism, Constitutional conservatism, and anticommunism; minutes and treasurer reports from club meetings; resolutions; speeches; photographs; Republican campaign material; and membership cards and applications. A strength of this collection is the detailed political correspondence reflecting the time period.
Organization and Arrangement
This collection has been arranged in the following series:
Series 1: Organizational records, 1962-1972
Series 2: Correspondence, 1962-1973
Related Material
California Republican Assembly Records (Collection 2039) Available at Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, UCLA.
South Pasadena Americanism Center Records (Collection 1844) Available at Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, UCLA.
California -- Politics and government -- 1951-.; Republican Party (Calif.); United Republicans of California -- Archives
- Series 1: Organizational records, 1962-1972
  Scope and Content
  The series consists of materials created by the United Republicans of California including organizational records, leadership manual, preamble, publications, meeting minutes, political pamphlets, brochures and newspaper clippings.
  Organization and Arrangement
  Series is arranged chronologically.
  - Bylaws and platforms, 1962-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Preamble: Zebold, circa 1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Leadership manual, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Board of Governors meeting, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - UROC binder, 1963-1971 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
    Includes memos, minutes, and agendas.
  - News clippings and Goldwater press, 1963-1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Pamphlets, 1963-1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Series 2: Correspondence, 1962-1973
  Contains the correspondence of Republican party members including E. Richard Barnes, Jane Crosby, Joe Crosby (past Los Angeles County chairman), Rus Walton, Robert Blake, John Harmer, Glen Lipscomb and Mrs. Don H. Rose.
  Series is arranged alphabetically.
  - Barnes, E. Richard, 1967-1971 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Crosby, Jane: resignation correspondence, John Ryan for state chairman vs. Walter Hintzen, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Crosby, Joe, 1962-1973 (Box 2, Folder 3-8)
  - Walton, Rus, 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Other: Robert Blake, John Harmer, Gilen Lipscomb, Mrs. Don H. Rose, 1964-1972 (Box 2, Folder 10)